<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on COMM 2100 with Kristen</title>
    <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on COMM 2100 with Kristen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 15th-week class (Tuesday, 11/28)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</guid>
      <description>Cultivation Theory A quite objective theory in the socio-psycological tradition and socio-cultural tradition.
Theorist: George Gerbner
Key question: how media use affects the real world. How media makes people think about a very violent world. (especially heavy TV viewers)
Also, Gerbner viewed TV as a story teller.
1. TV has changed in three ways since this theory was originally constructed.  Abundance of choices One thing not change, is that many TV still emphasize on violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 14th-week class (Tuesday, Semiotics &#43; Uses and Gratifications)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</guid>
      <description>Semiotics A quite interpretive theory in the semiotic tradition
Theorist: Roland Barthes
1. Semiotics: the analysis of anything that can stand for something else sign = signifier &amp;amp; signified
2. Two sign systems  Denotative sign system: a descriptive sign without ideological content connotative sign system: a sign that has lost its historical referent  3. Why semiotics in mass communication because media technology can spread it quickly
4. Critique  semiotics has not generated a large community of agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 13th-week class (Feminist Standpoint Theory &#43; Muted Group Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/13th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/13th-week/</guid>
      <description>Feminist Standpoint Theory A relatively interpretive theory in the tradition of critical.
Critical scholars want to make changes, challenge unjustice.
Theorists: Sandra Harding; Julia Wood.
Basic assumption: people have difference opinions about the same situation.
1. Social location: our group memberships that shape our experiences of the worlds and our ways of understanding it Standpoint: a place from which to critically view the world around us.
Standpoint poses the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 12th-week class (Communication Accomodation Theory &#43; Face Negotiation Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/12th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/12th-week/</guid>
      <description>Communication Accommodation Theory A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological.
Theorist: Howard Giles (at UCSB)
Assumption: While we talk with someone from a different background, we aim to achieve mutual understanding. So we accommodate the conversation to understand each other.
Accommodation: Movement toward or away from others by changing your communication behavior.
e.g., different places; different generations;
It&amp;rsquo;s a about &amp;ldquo;Social Distance&amp;rdquo;: How similar or different we are from one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 11th-week class (Communicative Constitution of Organization)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/11th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/11th-week/</guid>
      <description>Communicative Constitution of Organization In socio-cultural tradition, relatively interpretive.
Theorist: Robert McPhee
Basic Idea: Communication constitutes/creates organization.
1）Constitution: Communication calls organizations into being
Sensemaking: Communication behaviors can reduce ambiguity.
2）Four flows of communication
 Membership negotiation: communication that regulates the extent to which a person is an organization member. [socialization - you are socializing into your role, and learning the land] Self-structuring: communication that shapes the relationships among an organization&amp;rsquo;s members – who is who Activity coordination: communication that accomplishes the organization&amp;rsquo;s work toward goals – how we get things done Institutional positioning: communication between an organization and external entities  3）Four principles of the flows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 10th-week class (Symbolic Convergence Theory &#43; Cultural Approaches to Organizations)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/10th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/10th-week/</guid>
      <description>Symbolic Convergence Theory In the middle of objective and interpretive, and in the tradition of rhetoric and socio-psychological
Theorist: Emest Bormann
Interested in how communication brings people together, within groups.
1. Sharing group fantasies creates symbolic convergence Fantasy: dramatizing messages, that is enthusiatically embraced by the group.
They become shared interpretations of an event, and these interpretations would fill a group&amp;rsquo;s needs.
2. Dramatizing message: imaginative language by a group member describing past, future, or outside events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 8th-week class (Rhetoric, Dramatism, and Narative Paradigm)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/8th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/8th-week/</guid>
      <description>Rhetoric In the tradition of rhetoric.
Also, it&amp;rsquo;s half objective and half interpretive.
It&amp;rsquo;s about arts, and also about persuasion.
Theorist: Aristotle.
1. Rhetoric: discovering all possible means of persuasion. Three different categories:
Forensic: emphasizes that people make decisions about past actions. For example, the scenario of a court is a place for forensics.
Epideictic: offer to pray/blame, to benefit a president day&amp;rsquo;s audience/situation.
Deliberative: political speaking. Generally, a deliberative speech is designed to influence votes, for a future policy/person in power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 7th-week class (Elaboration Likelihood Model&amp;Cognitive Dissonance Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/7th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/7th-week/</guid>
      <description>Elaboration Likelihood Model A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological (almost the most objective one)
Theorists: Richard Petty &amp;amp; John Cacioppo
Key question: How do you get someone to listen to you when you are making an argument?
1. There are two routes to persuasion: the central route and the peripheral route Central: high mental effort
Peripheral route: low mental effort
The mental effort is what the listener gives to the speaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 6th-week class (Communication Management Privacy, Media Multiplexity)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/6th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/6th-week/</guid>
      <description>Communication Management Privacy An interpretive theory in the tradition of socio-cultural and cybernetic
Theorist: Sandra Petronio
She cares about privacy in interpersonal communication, rather than self-disclosure.
1. Principle 1: People believe that we have privacy and we are obliged to care for that information. We set boundaries about our own privacy.
For example, in health, we need to close this information, which will impact our life, and we set the boundary, because of the liability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 5th-week class (Social Information Processing Theory &amp; Relational Dialectics Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/5th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/5th-week/</guid>
      <description>Social Information Processing Theory A highly objective theory in the socio-psychological tradition.
Theorist: Joseph Walther
Core question: Is it possible to build strong interpersonal relationship only online (without nonverbal cues)? - CMC [Computer Mediated Communication]
CMC: More than computer.
1. Assumption Assumption: Relationships grow only to the extent that people can gain information about each other.
Social Information —&amp;gt; Impression Formation —&amp;gt; Relationship Development
 Previous studies about CMC used a cues-filtered-out approach  Communication is impersonal or task-oriented F2F communication is richest due to verbal and nonverbal cue access Unclear social context cues leads to flaming or toxicity    2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 4th-week class (Social Penetration Theory &amp; Uncertainty Reduction Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/4th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/4th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Social Penetration Theory A highly objective theory in the socio-psychological tradition.
Theorist: Irwin Altman &amp;amp; Dalmas Taylor
 the theorists were interested how closeness is developed - through mutual self-disclosure  1. Metaphor: Onion - everyone has their comfort level of sharing themselves 1）Closeness develops if individuals proceed in a gradual, orderly fashion from superficial to intimate.
2）Outer layer: how we present ourselves in public space
core: who we are at the core of ourselves</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 3rd-week class (Symbolic Interactionism Theory &#43; Expectancy Violations Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/3rd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/3rd-week/</guid>
      <description>Symbolic Interactionism Theory A highly interpretive theory in the socio-cultural tradition. - people produce and reproduce culture in communication.
Theorist: George Herbert Mead
（He didn&amp;rsquo;t write the book. His students recorded his minds in the book Mind, Self and Society
1. Principles 1）Principle #1: Humans act toward people or things on the basis of the meaning they assign to them.
stimulus -&amp;gt; interpretation -&amp;gt; response
 When we do verbal/non-verbal communication, we have guessings about what will be the response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 1st-week(2nd) class (Theory Traditions and Standards)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday Review: the scale from objective to interpretive Interpretive scholars: put all the experiences (from them/the participants) to create meaning and multiple realities
Objective scholars: put the theory out of the maths/models
Different standards 1. Objective theories: scientific standards   prediction of future events: Will people repeat the same behaviors?
Sometimes human behaviors cannot be predictable. But most of the times, it will predict very well.
How to define the prediction: the confidence interval in quantitative research - 95%</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 1st-week class (Communication and Theory)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</guid>
      <description>Communication and Theory - the Concept 1. Communication is the relational process of creating and interpreting messages that elicit a response  message: a stimulus that a source sends to a receiver creation of message: The communicator makes a conscious choice of message form and substance interpretation of message: &amp;ldquo;people mean things&amp;rdquo; a relational process: the communication happen between people, and changes the connection among people messages that elicit a response: &amp;ldquo;You cannot not communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
