<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes_not_showns on COMM 2100 with Kristen</title>
    <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes_not_showns on COMM 2100 with Kristen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 15th-week class (Tuesday, 11/28)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</guid>
      <description>Cultivation Theory A quite objective theory in the socio-psycological tradition and socio-cultural tradition.
Theorist: George Gerbner
Key question: how media use affects the real world. How media makes people think about a very violent world. (especially heavy TV viewers)
Also, Gerbner viewed TV as a story teller.
1. TV has changed in three ways since this theory was originally constructed.  Abundance of choices One thing not change, is that many TV still emphasize on violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 14th-week class (Tuesday, 11/21)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</guid>
      <description>Semiotics A quite interpretive theory in the semiotic tradition
Theorist: Roland Barthes
1. Semiotics: the analysis of anything that can stand for something else sign = signifier &amp;amp; signified
2. Two sign systems  Denotative sign system: a descriptive sign without ideological content connotative sign system: a sign that has lost its historical referent  3. Why semiotics in mass communication because media technology can spread it quickly
4. Critique  semiotics has not generated a large community of agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 13th-week class (Tuesday, 11/14)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/13th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/13th-week/</guid>
      <description>Muted Group Theory Critical tradition, Interpretive.
Theorist: Kramarae
Muted group: low-power group who must change that language when communicating publicly.
e.g., Women&amp;rsquo;s thoughts are devalued, so they need to change the language to make it easier.
1. Reason: Power discrepancies Power discrepancies between the sexes ensure that women will view the world differently than men.
2. Gatekeepers: editors and other arbiters of culture who determine what will appear in the mass media It assumed that women were excluded from publication and media representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 12th-week class (Tuesday, 11/7, Thursday, 11/9)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/12th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/12th-week/</guid>
      <description>Communication Accommodation Theory A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological.
Theorist: Howard Giles
Assumption: While we talk with someone from a different background, we aim to achieve mutual understanding. So we accommodate the conversation to understand each other.
Accommodation: Movement toward or away from others by changing your communication behavior.
e.g., different places; different generations;
It&amp;rsquo;s a about &amp;ldquo;Social Distance&amp;rdquo;: How similar or different we are from one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 11th-week class (Tuesday, 10/31)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/11th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/11th-week/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, Cultural Approaches to Organizations + CCO 1. Methodology: Ethnography  Who people in a culture think they are, what they think they are doing, and to what and they think they are doing it. Highly interpretive It starts from observation, and the object is to create thick description – cover thoughts, emotions, intentions, motives  Three forms of communication which provided helpful access to the unique shared meanings within an organization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 9th-week class (Tuesday, 10/17)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/9th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/9th-week/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, Dramatism A theory leaning to interpretive, in the tradition of rhetoric.
Rhetorical tradition: Communication as social address.
Key question: Why did people choose the words that they chose? To determine the motivation behind their message.
Could be considered as a theory, but also could be considered as a method.
Theorist: Kenneth Burke
1. Dramatism is a technique of analysis of language and thought as modes of action rather than as means of conveying information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 8th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,10/10,10/12)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/8th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/8th-week/</guid>
      <description>Rhetoric In the tradition of rhetoric.
Also, it&amp;rsquo;s half objective and half interpretive.
It&amp;rsquo;s about arts, and also about persuasion.
Theorist: Aristotle.
1. Rhetoric: discovering all possible means of persuasion. Three different categories:
Forensic: emphasizes that people make decisions about past actions. For example, the scenario of a court is a place for forensics.
Epideictic: offer to pray/blame, to benefit a president day&amp;rsquo;s audience/situation.
Deliberative: political speaking. Generally, a deliberative speech is designed to influence votes, for a future policy/person in power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
