<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes_not_showns on COMM 2100 with Kristen</title>
    <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes_not_showns on COMM 2100 with Kristen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 15th-week class (Tuesday, 11/28)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/15th-week/</guid>
      <description>Cultivation Theory A quite objective theory in the socio-psycological tradition and socio-cultural tradition.
Theorist: George Gerbner
Key question: how media use affects the real world. How media makes people think about a very violent world. (especially heavy TV viewers)
Also, Gerbner viewed TV as a story teller.
1. TV has changed in three ways since this theory was originally constructed.  Abundance of choices One thing not change, is that many TV still emphasize on violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 14th-week class (Tuesday, 11/21)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/14th-week/</guid>
      <description>Semiotics A quite interpretive theory in the semiotic tradition
Theorist: Roland Barthes
1. Semiotics: the analysis of anything that can stand for something else sign = signifier &amp;amp; signified
2. Two sign systems  Denotative sign system: a descriptive sign without ideological content connotative sign system: a sign that has lost its historical referent  3. Why semiotics in mass communication because media technology can spread it quickly
4. Critique  semiotics has not generated a large community of agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 13th-week class (Tuesday, 11/14)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/13th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes_not_shown/13th-week/</guid>
      <description>Muted Group Theory Critical tradition, Interpretive.
Theorist: Kramarae
Muted group: low-power group who must change that language when communicating publicly.
e.g., Women&amp;rsquo;s thoughts are devalued, so they need to change the language to make it easier.
1. Reason: Power discrepancies Power discrepancies between the sexes ensure that women will view the world differently than men.
2. Gatekeepers: editors and other arbiters of culture who determine what will appear in the mass media It assumed that women were excluded from publication and media representation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
