<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Class on COMM 2100 with Kristen</title>
    <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Class on COMM 2100 with Kristen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 2nd-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,8/29,8/31)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday Review: the scale from objective to interpretive Interpretive scholars: put all the experiences (from them/the participants) to create meaning and multiple realities
Objective scholars: put the theory out of the maths/models
Different standards 1. Objective theories: scientific standards   prediction of future events: Will people repeat the same behaviors?
Sometimes human behaviors cannot be predictable. But most of the times, it will predict very well.
How to define the prediction: the confidence interval in quantitative research - 95%</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 1st-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,8/22,8/24)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</guid>
      <description>2nd Class, Thursday 1. Communication is the relational process of creating and interpreting messages that elicit a response  message: a stimulus that a source sends to a receiver creation of message: The communicator makes a conscious choice of message form and substance interpretation of message: &amp;ldquo;people mean things&amp;rdquo; a relational process: the communication happen between people, and changes the connection among people messages that elicit a response: &amp;ldquo;You cannot not communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
