<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Class on COMM 2100 with Kristen</title>
    <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Class on COMM 2100 with Kristen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 12th-week class (Tuesday, 11/7, Thursday, 11/9)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/12th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/12th-week/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, Communication Accommodation Theory A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological.
Theorist: Howard Giles
Assumption: While we talk with someone from a different background, we aim to achieve mutual understanding. So we accommodate the conversation to understand each other.
Accommodation: Movement toward or away from others by changing your communication behavior.
e.g., different places; different generations;
It&amp;rsquo;s a about &amp;ldquo;Social Distance&amp;rdquo;: How similar or different we are from one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 11th-week class (Tuesday, 10/31)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/11th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/11th-week/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, Cultural Approaches to Organizations + CCO 1. Methodology: Ethnography  Who people in a culture think they are, what they think they are doing, and to what and they think they are doing it. Highly interpretive It starts from observation, and the object is to create thick description – cover thoughts, emotions, intentions, motives  Three forms of communication which provided helpful access to the unique shared meanings within an organization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 9th-week class (Tuesday, 10/17)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/9th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/9th-week/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, Dramatism A theory leaning to interpretive, in the tradition of rhetoric.
Rhetorical tradition: Communication as social address.
Key question: Why did people choose the words that they chose? To determine the motivation behind their message.
Could be considered as a theory, but also could be considered as a method.
Theorist: Kenneth Burke
1. Dramatism is a technique of analysis of language and thought as modes of action rather than as means of conveying information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 8th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,10/10,10/12)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/8th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/8th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Cognitive Dissonance Theory A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological
In the section on social influence/persuasion
Theorist: Leon Festinger
Interested in the dissonance between what people know and what people do.
Assumption: People will do everything to reduce dissonance, for the reason of safety.
Cognitive Dissonance: A distressing mental state caused by inconsistency between a person and the person&amp;rsquo;s beliefs, or a belief and an action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 7th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,10/3,10/5)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/7th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/7th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Exam 1 2nd Class, Thursday, Elaboration Likelihood Model A highly objective theory in the tradition of socio-psychological (almost the most objective one)
Theorists: Richard Petty &amp;amp; John Cacioppo
Key question: How do you get someone to listen to you when you are making an argument?
1. There are two routes to persuasion: the central route and the peripheral route Central: high mental effort
Peripheral route: low mental effort</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 6th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,9/26,9/28)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/6th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/6th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Communication Management Privacy An interpretive theory in the tradition of socio-cultural
Theorist: Sandra Petronio
She cares about privacy in interpersonal communication, rather than self-disclosure.
1. Principle 1: People believe that we have privacy and we are obliged to care for that information. We set boundaries about our own privacy.
For example, in health, we need to close this information, which will impact our life, and we set the boundary, because of the liability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 5th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,9/19,9/21)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/5th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/5th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Social Information Processing Theory A highly objective theory in the socio-psychological tradition.
Theorist: Joseph Walther
Core question: Is it possible to build strong interpersonal relationship only online (without nonverbal cues)? - CMC [Computer Mediated Communication]
CMC: More than computer.
1. Assumption Assumption: Relationships grow only to the extent that people can gain information about each other.
Social Information —&amp;gt; Impression Formation —&amp;gt; Relationship Development
 Previous studies about CMC used a cues-filtered-out approach  Communication is impersonal or task-oriented F2F communication is richest due to verbal and nonverbal cue access Unclear social context cues leads to flaming or toxicity    2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 4th-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,9/12,9/14)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/4th-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/4th-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Social Penetration Theory A highly objective theory in the socio-psychological tradition.
Theorist: Irwin Altman &amp;amp; Dalmas Taylor
1. Metaphor: Onion - everyone has their comfort level of sharing themselves 1）Closeness develops if individuals proceed in a gradual, orderly fashion from superficial to intimate.
2）Outer layer: how we present ourselves in public space
core: who we are at the core of ourselves
3）self-disclosure has both depth and breadth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 3rd-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,9/5,9/7)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/3rd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/3rd-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday, Symbolic Interactionism Theory A highly interpretive theory in the socio-cultural tradition.
Theorist: George Herbert Mead
（He didn&amp;rsquo;t write the book. His students recorded his minds in the book Mind, Self and Society
1. Principles 1）Principle #1: Humans act toward people or things on the basis of the meaning they assign to them.
stimulus -&amp;gt; interpretation -&amp;gt; response
 When we do verbal/non-verbal communication, we have guessings about what will be the response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 2nd-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,8/29,8/31)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-2nd-week/</guid>
      <description>1st Class, Tuesday Review: the scale from objective to interpretive Interpretive scholars: put all the experiences (from them/the participants) to create meaning and multiple realities
Objective scholars: put the theory out of the maths/models
Different standards 1. Objective theories: scientific standards   prediction of future events: Will people repeat the same behaviors?
Sometimes human behaviors cannot be predictable. But most of the times, it will predict very well.
How to define the prediction: the confidence interval in quantitative research - 95%</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the 1st-week class (Tuesday &amp; Thursday,8/22,8/24)</title>
      <link>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comm2100.kristenjz.com/notes/tues-1st-week/</guid>
      <description>2nd Class, Thursday 1. Communication is the relational process of creating and interpreting messages that elicit a response  message: a stimulus that a source sends to a receiver creation of message: The communicator makes a conscious choice of message form and substance interpretation of message: &amp;ldquo;people mean things&amp;rdquo; a relational process: the communication happen between people, and changes the connection among people messages that elicit a response: &amp;ldquo;You cannot not communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
